A Finding Aid to the Foster Brothers Records, 1875-1973, (bulk 1893-1942), in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Printed Material, 1893-1947; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.25 Linear feet (Box 10, OV 25)
  The majority of printed material relates to advertising and consists of catalogs and brochures about frames, mirrors, and published reproductions. Unless otherwise noted, all items were produced by or are about Foster Brothers. Scrapbooks in Series 7 contain additional printed material.
  - Advertising, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Advertising (R. H. Macy and Co., featuring Foster Brothers' mirrors, frames, and reproductions), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Broadside, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 10)
    (see: OV 25)
  - Brochures about Reproductions (not Foster Brothers), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Brochures and Catalogs, 1890s-1930s; undated; Archival Resource Key; 3 Folders (Box 10, Folder 12-14)
    see also OV 25
  - Business Card of Helen Foster, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, About/Mentioning Foster Brothers, undated; 1893-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, About Picture Frames, 1934; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, Miscellaneous Subjects, undated; 1893; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1893-1894; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Frame Labels, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Order Form for Reproductions, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Pamphlet about History of 2 Park Street, Boston (Houghton Mifflin Co.), 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Reproductions of Silhouettes Published by Foster Brothers, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Broadside, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 25)
  - Brochures and Catalogs, Archival Resource Key (Box OV 25)
- Scrapbooks, 1906-1942; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 1.3 Linear feet (Boxes 10, 12, BV 20-22)
  8 volumes of scrapbooks contain printed material including clippings, advertising material, brochures and catalogs, form letters, and reproductions of miniatures and silhouettes published by Foster Brothers.
  - Vol. 1: Advertising, 1906-1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Vol. 2: Advertising, 1915-1923; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 25)
    (see BV 20)
  - Vol. 3: Advertising, 1934-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 26)
    (see BV 21)
  - Vol. 4: Advertising in Magazines, 1918-1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Vol. 5: Advertising in Magazines, 1924-1934, undated; Archival Resource Key; (disbound volume; see Box 12) (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Vol. 6: Advertising in Magazines, 1927-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Vol. 7: Reproductions of Miniatures and Silhouettes (published by Foster Brothers), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 30)
    (See: Box 12)
  - Vol. 8: Reproductions of Drawings by Alfred Shaw, Francis Getty, Kenneth Conant (copyrighted and published by Foster Brothers), 1921-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 31)
    (see BV 22)
  - Loose Items [from unidentified scrapbook(s)], undated; 1924-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Vol. 5: Advertising in Magazines, undated; 1924-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 12)
  - Vol. 7: Reproductions of Miniatures and Silhouettes (published by Foster Brothers), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12)
  - Vol. 2: Advertising, 1915-1923; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box BV 20)
  - Vol. 3: Advertising, 1934-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box BV 21)
  - Vol. 8: Reproductions of Drawings by Alfred Shaw, Francis Getty, Kenneth Conant (copyrighted and published by Foster Brothers), 1921-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box BV 22)
- Family Papers, 1875-1973; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 6 Folders Box 10
  Family papers consist of a small number of personal papers of Foster Brothers founders, John Roy and Stephen Bartlett Foster, and also of Helen Foster Osborne (John's daughter). A letter from Edward Everett Hale, 1889, accepting an invitation addressed to Mr. Foster could have been intended for either Stephen or John Foster. Also included are a silhouette of John R. Foster cut by Doris Burdick, and his personal account book with some brief diary entries that pre-date the establishment of Foster Brothers by more than a decade. Of particular interest is Helen Foster Osborne's 1973 reminiscence of having her portrait painted by William Paxton in 1923. Helen Foster Osborne's correspondence with Ernest Donnelley, post-dating the closing of Foster Brothers, concerns the sale of printing plates and dies from the miniature reproduction business.
  - To Mr. Foster, Letter from Edward Everett Hale, 1889; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - John R. Foster, Account Book, 1875-1880; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - John R. Foster, Silhouette Cut by Doris Burdick, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Stephen B Foster, Will, 1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Helen Foster Osborne, Correspondence with Ernest Donnnelly, 1945-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Helen Foster Osborne, Photograph of Portrait of her by William Paxton (with reminiscence), 1923, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 38)
- Photographs, circa 1880s-1918; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 5 Folders (Box 10)
  Photographs are of the Foster brothers, John Roy and Stephen Bartlett Foster. One portrait of each is in a "Keepsake Frame," a popular item designed and manufactured by Foster Brothers. Other people appearing in photographs are employees, most of whom are unidentified. Also included are pictures of the Foster Brothers' first frame factory on Cambridge Street, picturing the exterior of the factory and the "fitting room."
  - People, Employees, 1896; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - People, Foster, John Roy, 1880s-circa 1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - People, Foster, Stephen Bartlett, circa 1880s-1890s; undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Places, Foster Brothers Factory, Cambridge St. (exterior and "fitting room"), 1890s-1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Places, John and Stephen Foster, Charles Street Apartment, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 43)